Stanley Ari Cohen

Morrisville, NC 27560 (760)846-6814 | a12n@mac.com

Professional Summary

Senior Software Engineer with over 6 years of full stack experience specializing in .NET, Angular, and MS SQL. Likes working closely with clients to ensure quality deliveries. Passionate about APIs, unit tests, and cross-team collaborations.

Experience

Tyler Technologies

Sept 2018 - Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Facilitate team scrum and retrospective meetings for 13-person development team.
- Lead development on several contracts totaling >\$700K
- Trained support representatives in SQL to perform routine data fixes independently, reducing reliance on developers and saving ~800 hours of engineering time anually.
- Resolved the most support tickets on the team 2 years in a row (150% more than the next most productive developer).
- Adhered to the Test Driven Development paradigm, creating and maintaining >1000 unit tests.

Thales USA

July 2017 – Aug 2018

Software Engineer

- Troubleshooted and identified systems issues in the lab prior to them being fielded.
- Helped train and develop 5 Customer IVV and GIIV teams to ensure a better understanding of our system.
- Developed automation scripts to stress test systems, reducing QA time by 15 man-hours per installation.

La Costa Kids

June 2011 – June 2015

Software Consultant

- Designed and implemented an Objective-C solution to manage >30K transactions and >5K customers' information across 2 physical store locations.
- Saved 100+ hours per year of cashier-hours looking up and entering transactions.
- Built 3 reports and an HTML dashboard that provided data insight into benchmark marketing trends and simplified annual tax reporting.

FPAP Football Pool

June 2011 - June 2015

Software Consultant

- Designed and implemented a Python solution to manage manage players' betting choices and check them against live scores on NFL.com.
- Saved the pool manager 10+ hours per week.
- Delivered results to players days earlier and eliminated all data entry errors.

Education

University California Riverside

Sept 2013 – June 2017

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Skills

- Software Language Skills: C# (>10K lines), C/C++, Python, SQL, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Bash
- Frameworks: .NET, Entity Framework, NUnit, IdeaBlade, Infragistics
- Tools & More: Agile methodology, Git, Mercurial SCM, RESTful APIs, Postman, JIRA